<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Chow</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Chow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&#39;m Eric! Currently, I am a medical student at the Chicago Medical School at the Rosalind Franklin University. Previously, I was a Biostatistician at Stanford Medicine in the Quantitative Sciences Unit where I worked with a variety of physicians on study design, power calculation, and analyses. Before that, I was a senior research data analyst at Johns Hopkins, where I worked with some really cool doctors and epidemiologists on kidney and liver transplant problems in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science</title>
      <link>/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 Kidney Transplant Web App What does this COVID-19 pandemic mean for the thousands of people on the kidney transplant waitlist? Should surgeons wait for it to be over? Are these patients at a greater risk going to dialysis every week? I worked with some Hopkins experts to make a simulation. Check out the App.
Lung Cancer Risk Factor R Package A person&#39;s smoking history can inform them about their risk of lung cancer, but what about those of us who have never smoked?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search &amp; Rescue</title>
      <link>/sar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sar/</guid>
      <description>I have been a Mountain Search and Rescue Volunteer with the Bay Area Mountain Rescue Unit (BAMRU) in California since 2018. In my first year, I logged 350+ operational hours in over a dozen searches in the Sierras and all over the state. It&#39;s not easy! Training in my first-year took 500hrs (my training is still ongoing) and I have to work effectively and safely with my team-mates under circumstances of extreme pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pubmed</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My H-index on Scopus is 17. I can be found as Eric KH Chow on the pubmeds. Or if you want to get in touch, you can contact me or checkout my social media. A selection of works I was involved in:
 Church E et al, Pregnancy after direct cerebral bypass for Moyamoya disease. J Neuro Surg; Nov 15, 2019. Pargaonkar V et al, Accuracy of non-invasive stress testing in women and men with angina in the absence of obstructive coronary artery disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art</title>
      <link>/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/art/</guid>
      <description>Medical Illustrations I could always draw very well. I had an elementary school art teacher who would always say that I had &amp;ldquo;the eye&amp;rdquo; in a very freaky ominous way. I&#39;m not sure where this eye is, but I think I just have very excellent fine motor skills. I started drawing like this when I was about 11 years old. At the time, my favorite subject were dinosaurs.
 Here&#39;s another example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can get in touch with me about research, biostatistics, data-science, medicine, search and rescue, climbing, adventuring, (or anything really) by email: eric.chow@my.rfums.org
Linkedin | Github | Instagram | Mountain Project
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>