<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Chow</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Chow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Eric! Currently, I am a medical student at the Chicago Medical School at the Rosalind Franklin University with interests in wilderness medicine, critical care, and also radiology. Previously, I was a Biostatistician at Stanford Medicine in the Quantitative Sciences Unit where I worked with a variety of physicians on study design, power calculation, and analyses. Before that, I was a senior research data analyst at Johns Hopkins, where I worked with some really cool doctors and epidemiologists on kidney and liver transplant problems in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art</title>
      <link>/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/art/</guid>
      <description>Medical Illustrations I could always draw very well. I had an elementary school art teacher who would always say that I had &amp;ldquo;the eye&amp;rdquo; in a very freaky ominous way. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where this eye is, but I think I just have very excellent fine motor skills. I started drawing like this when I was about 11 years old. At the time, my favorite subject were dinosaurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/</guid>
      <description>Lung Cancer Risk Factor R Package A person&amp;rsquo;s smoking history can inform them about their risk of lung cancer, but what about those of us who have never smoked? can&amp;rsquo;t we get lung cancer too, and how do you figure out our risk? Along w Summer Han, I developed an R package that simulates other lung cancer risk factors using the smoking history generator developed by CISNET. Check it out on my github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAR</title>
      <link>/sar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sar/</guid>
      <description>I have been a Mountain Search and Rescue Volunteer with the Bay Area Mountain Rescue Unit (BAMRU) in California since 2018. In my first year, I logged 350+ operational hours over 13 searches in the Sierras and all over the state. I was awarded Rookie of the year.
As a mountain SAR volunteer, I was on-call 24-7 to respond to lost hikers and climbers in the most difficult and remote mountain terrain in California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pubmed</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My H-index on Scopus is 15. I can be found as Eric KH Chow on the pubmeds. Or if you want to get in touch, you can contact me or checkout my social media
 Treat E, Chow EKH, Peirpert JD, Waterman A, Segev DL, Veale J. Outcomes of Shipped Kidney Paired Donation with Additional Cold Ischemia Time. (in draft) Chow EKH, Massie AB, Luo X, Wickliffe CE, Gentry SE, Cameron AM, Segev DL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can get in touch with me about research, biostatistics, data-science, medicine, search and rescue, climbing, adventuring, (or anything really) by email: echow8@my.rfums.org
Also, do you climb? do you have an adventure coming up and need a partner? Tell me about it! I lead 5.8 trad, 5.10c sport. Here&amp;rsquo;s my mountain project.
instagram github linkedin  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>