<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Chow</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Chow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Eric! Currently, I work at Stanford Univeristy in the Quantitative Sciences Unit as a Biostatistician. Before that, I spent 5 years at Johns Hopkins Univeristy in Baltimore, where I worked with some really cool doctors and epidemiologists on kidney and liver transplant problems in the US. I&amp;rsquo;m all about improving and saving lives.
I&amp;rsquo;m a pro at survival analysis, Markov modelling, decision processing modelling, regression, and stochastic simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art</title>
      <link>/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/art/</guid>
      <description>Medical Illustrations I could always draw very well. I had an elementary school art teacher who would always say that I had &amp;ldquo;the eye&amp;rdquo; in a very freaky ominous way. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where this eye is, but I think I just have very excellent fine motor skills. I started drawing like this when I was about 11 years old. At the time, my favorite subject were dinosaurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work</title>
      <link>/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/</guid>
      <description>Spontaneous Coronary Artery Dissection I am the statistical lead on a multi-center study of SCAD. I advise the primary investigators on study design, matching of cases and controls, appropriate statistical methods, and data collection. I have a junior statistician who helps me with this, which is nice.
Liver Simulated Allocation Model Allocation of donated organs to people with liver disease is challenging in the US. I worked with mathematicians, data from the Scientific Registry for Transplant Recipients, and used simulation models to study hypothetical allocation systems that give people with liver disease a fairer chance at a life-saving liver transplant, regardless of where they live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pubmed</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My H-index on Scopus is 10. I can be found as Eric KH Chow on the pubmeds. Or if you want to get in touch, you can contact me or checkout my social media
 Treat E, Chow EKH, Peirpert JD, Waterman A, Segev DL, Veale J. Outcomes of Shipped Kidney Paired Donation with Additional Cold Ischemia Time. (in draft) Chow EKH, Massie AB, Luo X, Wickliffe CE, Gentry SE, Cameron AM, Segev DL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Do you have an interesting problem in medicine? Do you have lots of data? Get in touch with me! (echow8@stanford.edu) I&amp;rsquo;d love to help you figure it out. I&amp;rsquo;m available for statistical consultation, or more involved analytical work as well.
Also, do you climb? do you have an adventure coming up and need a partner? Tell me about it! I lead 5.8 trad, 5.10c sport. Here&amp;rsquo;s my mountain project.
instagram github linkedin  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>